CURRICULUM VITAE

Dmitry Ryabokon

Summary

- o Remote R&D engineer with deep experience in
- Convolutional neural networks
- Computer Vision
- o Data science
- Artificial intelligence
- Machine learning
- Image processing
- o Pattern recognition
- Pre-sales consulting support

Technology stack

ML: TensorFlow, Keras, Scikit-learn, Pandas, Matplotlib, Numpy, SciPy

o ComputerVision: OpenCV, Pillow, Tesseract

Math: Python, Matlab, R

o C++: WinAPI

o 3D: DirectX, OpenGL

SQL: MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL

NoSQL: MongoDB

Web: Postman, Fiddler

o IDE: PyCharm, MS Visual Studio, NetBeans, IDEA, KDevelop

CASE tools: Visual Paradigm for UML, Rational Rose, Enterprise architect

Version control: Git, SVN, CSV

Doc: Doxygen, JasperReports
ERP\CRM: Cognos, Jira, SugarCRM
Agile: Scrum, XP, FDD, TDD

Education

2002-2005: Cybernetic Center of the National Academy of Science of Ukraine, PhD
2002 : Dresden Technical University (Germany), faculty of artificial intelligence

1996-2002 : National Technical University of Ukraine, physical & engineering faculty, MD

Experience

2017 - now: Cogniance

Activities

- Running various engineering projects
- Day to day cooperation with product team and project stakeholders
- o Post-production support of the products: maintenance and improvements
- o Addressing and resolving issues escalated from end users
- Continuous improvement of the product: system design, UX, functionality and features
- Managing of prioritized product roadmap and backlog
- Enhancing and following best engineering practices for CI/CD/Test automation/Performance testing

Technologies/tools/frameworks

- Python
- o Git, Jenkins, Jira
- CI/CD/Test automation, Performance testing

2013 - 2017: Zoral Labs

Projects

- o Implementing Decision engine for customer's online e-lending systems
- o Business rules management for credit risk decisioning

Activities

- o R&D
- o Software engineering
- Requirements management
- System design
- o Project delivery management
- Managing of prioritized product roadmap and backlog
- o Enhancing and following agile-based best-practices
- Pre-sales consultative support

Technologies/tools/frameworks

- o Python, Git, Trac, Wiki
- o R, AI/ML models' library

2009 - 2013: Luxoft

Projects

- Reference Data Services development of master data management tools. Development of Data Warehouse architecture guiding principles.
- Operations Portal developing of BI tools for analysis of capacity, cost per trade, resource utilization and other performance indicators (KPI's) for Global Business Solutions.

Activities

- Running multiple projects (data mining tools, analysis of transaction costs impact, trade management lifecycle, incident management, reference data management)
- o Adopting Agile Delivery practices in rapidly changing, collaborative business environment
- Establishing processes for secure, high-quality service-oriented deliverables
- Building a strong, engaged core team of business SMEs, resource optimization
- Ensure timely project resource management

Technologies/tools/frameworks

- o Java, C++, JS, Python, Git, Gerrit, Jira, Wiki, WebKit, Enyo
- o Informatica, MDM Hub, PegaRules
- o Flex, Oracle, Java, IBM Cognos, QlikView

2007 - 2009: ITT-consulting

Activities:

- o Running various types of projects (R&D, VoIP, ERP, CRM, Web, etc.)
- System/architecture design
- Researching of technology trends and innovation in AI/ML
- Customer communication, technical requirements specification
- Development and implementation of corporate IT-strategy
- Pre-sales consulting

Technologies/tools/frameworks:

- o C++, Asterisk
- o DirectX
- Sugar CRM, Joomla, MySQL

2006 - 2007: Innovative marketing

Activities:

- o Implementing of expert decision-making system to optimize targeted marketing for clients.
- o Forecasting of customer purchasing capabilities and analysis of target advertisement
- People coordination and management, outsource team management
- o Achieved target revenue and gross margin quotas via production chain improvement
- Provided internal trainings (UML, software design, risk management, statistical pattern recognition)

Achievements:

- Effective target marketing strategy that improved profit up to 40%
- Analytical tools for aligning multi-channel advertisement strategy according to clients target customer groups/segments

Foreign languages

- o English fluent
- o Russian fluent
- German basic level

Contacts

- o github.com/dryabokon
- linkedin.com/in/ryabokon/
- o d.ryabokon@gmail.com